# DANIEL KELLEY, PMP, PMI-ACP

www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-kelley1 • https://github.com/DK-2021

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Adaptable, organized and dependable US Army Special Operations veteran. Someone who is always seeking to optimize a process or develop a solution to a problem. Transitioning into software engineering with a fundamental understanding of full stack software development. Possess and have maintained a Secret Clearance for more than ten years.

### **RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS**

- Project Management Professional (PMP), 2021
- Project Management Institute Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP), 2021
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), 2021
- Microsoft Technology Associate Software Development Fundamentals (MTA 98-361), 2021
- NC State University Artificial Intelligence Academy Foundations Course, 2021

## **SKILLS**

- Intermediate: C#, Windows, macOS
- Novice: Python, Git/GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MS SQL Server, MS Azure, .NET, Linux (ubuntu)

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Microsoft Software and Systems Academy

# **Cloud Application Development Student**

January 2022 - May 2022

- Selected for a highly competitive program that supports transitioning service members as they gain the professional and technical knowledge necessary to enter the technology industry.
- Studied in **Cloud** Application Development, learning to design, build, and support applications and programs.
- Gained fundamental skills in C#, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Git and Object-Oriented Programming.
- Learned conceptual frameworks for Web Application Development, ASP.NET MVC, and Azure Application Development.
- Built, modified, and ran more than 100 queries against T-SQL databases via SQL Server Management Studio for data analysis and interpretation.

# 95th Civil Affairs Brigade (Army Special Operations)

## **Assistant Operations Supervisor**

October 2020 - January 2022

- Assumed the Operational Supervisor position for four months during a company realignment; maintained both
  positions for four months and managed 15 coworkers to meet all organizational directives.
- Managed the company's classified personnel recovery database; increased the company's compliance from 80% to 100% when audited by a third-party.
- Published over 35 organizational bulletins that were distributed to more than 200 coworkers weekly; informed
  coworkers of company-wide events and notified of career enhancing opportunities.

# **Civil Affairs Specialist**

**October 2017 – October 2020** 

- Coordinated four humanitarian assistance programs valued at \$45,000; enabled the U.S. Embassy access to three strategic locations in Trinidad and Tobago.
- Managed the expenses of **\$20,000 USD** worth of organizational funds while working internationally; utilized the funds appropriately enabling the team to **increase** its overall capacity to achieve objectives.
- Managed and coordinated over 200 tasks to different teams in support of organizational functions; all tasks'
  deadlines were met and adherence to the enterprise's readiness model standard was maintained

#### **PROJECTS**

Random Restaurant Picker – C#, SQL, XML, XAML

A team project that used an API of a given location to help select a type of restaurant to eat at based on certain user preferences. Utilized GitHub with teammates, allowing for each member to work with the project's latest version.

• **Personal Webpage** – HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, MS Paint (<a href="https://dk-2021.github.io/MyWebsite/">https://dk-2021.github.io/MyWebsite/</a>) Using GitHub as a host, based on a website template, reconfigured the HTML, CSS and JavaScript to be used as a personal website. The website described my abilities, links to work and experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Criminal Justice, University of Massachusetts, MA May 2011